[
    {
        "question": "All countries are members of the ......system.",
        "options": [
            "International",
            "Bilingual"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Logo",
        "options": [
            "BRICS",
            "Lotus"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "India conducted her first nuclear tests in ......",
        "options": [
            "1947",
            "1957",
            "1967",
            "1974"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Some ...... countries participated in the military pacts led either by American or the Soviet Union.",
        "options": [
            "Latin American",
            "Asian African"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "...... : Non-alignment :: Atal Bihari Vajpayee :: Sino-Indian relations.",
        "options": [
            "Rajiv Gandhi",
            "Indira Gandhi",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Pandit Nehru"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of CTBT",
        "options": [
            "Council of Treaty Behind Tech",
            "Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The ……… and ……… in the neighbouring countries is as important as that within our own country.",
        "options": [
            "Progress and Stability",
            "Peace and democracy",
            "Economy and political",
            "Peace and stability"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Some nations have a long coastline while some have plenty of",
        "options": [
            "Natural resource",
            "Wealth",
            "Mineral wealth",
            "Population"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "NNPT : Nuclear Non Proliferation :: CTBT : ………",
        "options": [
            "Countries Test Benefit Treaty",
            "Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The theoretical framework in which decisions regarding international relations are called ………",
        "options": [
            "Foreign policy",
            "Interdependence",
            "International politics",
            "Programme"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "……… is included in the national interest.",
        "options": [
            "Defence",
            "Protection",
            "Development",
            "Policy"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of NNPT",
        "options": [
            "Nuclear Non Proliferation Treaty",
            "Nuclear Nations Popular team"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "……… aimed at strengthening the economy of the country.",
        "options": [
            "Democracy",
            "Socialism",
            "Import - export",
            "Security"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "India has been consistently supporting efforts for ......",
        "options": [
            "Peace",
            "Security",
            "Disarmament",
            "Nuclear weapons"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "India's foreign policy became more ...... and dynamic in the second stage.",
        "options": [
            "Comprehensive",
            "Progressive",
            "Powerful",
            "Self-reliance"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The protection of our country independence sovereignty and integrity is the ...... national interest.",
        "options": [
            "Lowest",
            "Moderate",
            "Highest",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "...... Treaty have been made to stop the spread of nuclear weapons.",
        "options": [
            "ARC",
            "NNPT",
            "BRICS",
            "SAARC"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "An economically ...... Nation will not be able to maintain its independence.",
        "options": [
            "Weak",
            "Strong",
            "Rich",
            "Poor"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Geographical Location : ...... :: Economy :: Import-Export",
        "options": [
            "Economy",
            "Population",
            "Independent",
            "Parliament"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In second stage of India’s foreign policy relations with ...... strengthened.",
        "options": [
            "Russia",
            "America",
            "China",
            "Pakistan"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Peace and Freedom became the fundamental principle of ...... policy.",
        "options": [
            "Foreign policy",
            "Economic policy",
            "Co-operative",
            "Non-aligned"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "National Interest : Defence :: Foreign policy : ......",
        "options": [
            "Economy",
            "Co-operative",
            "Security",
            "Dependent"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "...... is also an important national interest.",
        "options": [
            "Development",
            "Social development",
            "Political development",
            "Economic development"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "1947 : first stage :: ...... : second stage",
        "options": [
            "1990",
            "1991",
            "1968",
            "1971"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In a democratic political system the nations ………. play a major role in evolving foreign policy.",
        "options": [
            "Government",
            "Protection",
            "Sovereignty",
            "Parliament"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    }
]